声音与发音。所以现在正是合适的时机，深入讲讲
sound, pronunciation. This is an opportune moment, then, to go into the quality of
据我观察，人们说外语时会紧绷起来，
your voice. In my observation, when people speak a foreign language, they tense up
喉咙也会绷紧，所以整个沟通风格听起来用力、挤压、紧张，
their throat, so their whole communication style sounds forced, pinched, strained,
不自然，或者带鼻音。外国学习者的声音通常也更高。
artificial, or nasal. The foreign speaker's voice is also generally higher
音高会高于理想状态。为了练习这种区别，
pitched than would be considered desirable. To practice the difference
要练习高低音高的区别，可以练 uh-oh。除此之外，
between high pitch and lower pitch, work on uh-oh. In addition to pitch, this
这个练习会让你分辨尖细的鼻音和低沉、饱满、悦耳的低音音色。
exercise will let you discover between a tinny nasal tone and a deep rich
波浪号表示鼻音；下面说明压低声音时
mellifluous basso profundo tone. The tilde is used to indicate a nasal sound. If you
试图靠撑开喉咙会得到奇怪、空洞的声音。
try to deepen your voice by expanding your throat, you'll end up with an odd hollow
sound.